Two years ago, after having served four years
قبل عامين، وعقب عملي لأربع سنوات
in the United States Marine Corps
في مشاة البحرية الأمريكية
and deployments to both Iraq and Afghanistan,
والخدمة العسكرية في كل من العراق وأفغانستان،
I found myself in Port-au-Prince, leading a team
وجدت نفسي في العاصمة بورت أو برنس، أقود فريقا
of veterans and medical professionals
من قدامى المحاربين وخبراء الطب
in some of the hardest-hit areas of that city,
في أحد أصعب الأماكن المنكوبة في المدينة،
three days after the earthquake.
بعد 3 أيام من ضربة الزلزال.
We were going to the places that nobody else wanted to go,
كنا نذهب إلى أماكن لم يرغب أحد في الذهاب إليها.
the places nobody else could go, and after three weeks,
أماكن لا يستطيع أي أحد أن يذهب إليها، وبعد ثلاثة أسابيع،
we realized something. Military veterans
وبعد 3 أسابيع، أدركنا شيئاً. قدامى محاربي الجيش
are very, very good at disaster response.
جيدون جداً في التعامل مع الكوارث.
And coming home, my cofounder and I,
بعد رجوعنا إلى الوطن، شريكي وأنا
we looked at it, and we said, there are two problems.
نظرنا إلى الأمر وقلنا، هناك مشكلتان.
The first problem is there's inadequate disaster response.
الأولى هي عدم كفاية الاستجابة للكوارث.
It's slow. It's antiquated. It's not using the best technology,
إنها بطيئة، إنها قديمة. إنها لا تستخدم أفضل التكنولوجيا،
and it's not using the best people.
وهي لا تستخدم أفضل الناس تدريباً."
The second problem that we became aware of
المشكلة الثانية هي أننا أصبحنا واعين
was a very inadequate veteran reintegration,
بنظام إعادة إدماج قدامى المحاربين غير الكافي.
and this is a topic that is front page news right now
وهذا هو الأمر، إنه في عناوين الأخبار الآن.
as veterans are coming home from Iraq and Afghanistan,
قدامى المحاربون هؤلاء عائدون إلى الوطن من العراق وأفغانستان
and they're struggling to reintegrate into civilian life.
وهم يعانون من أجل الإدماج في حياة مدنية.
And we sat here and we looked at these two problems,
لقد جلسنا هنا وتباحثنا هاتين المشكلتين،
and finally we came to a realization. These aren't problems.
وأخيراً توصلنا إلى حقيقة. هذه ليست مشاكل.
These are actually solutions. And what do I mean by that?
بل هي حلول في الواقع. ماذا أعني بقولي هذا؟
Well, we can use disaster response as an opportunity
حسنا، يمكننا استخدام الاستجابة للكارثة كفرصة
for service for the veterans coming home.
لتشغيل قدامى المحاربين العائدين إلى الوطن.
Recent surveys show that 92 percent of veterans want
مؤخراً أظهرت استطلاعات أن 92% من قدامى المحاربين يريدون
to continue their service when they take off their uniform.
مواصلة الخدمة عندما يخلعون الزي الرسمي.
And we can use veterans to improve disaster response.
ويمكننا استخدام قدامى المحاربين لتطوير الاستجابة للكوارث.
Now on the surface, this makes a lot of sense, and in 2010,
الآن، على السطح هذا يعني الكثير، وفي سنة 2010 ،
we responded to the tsunami in Chile,
استجبنا لكارثة تسونامي في شيلي،
the floods in Pakistan, we sent training teams to the Thai-Burma border.
والفيضان في باكستان، قمنا بإرسال فرق تدريب إلى الحدود التايلندية البورمية.
But it was earlier this year, when one of our
لكن بداية هذا العام، أحد
original members caused us to shift focus in the organization.
أعضائنا الأساسيين جعلنا نغيّر اهتمامنا في المؤسسة.
This is Clay Hunt. Clay was a Marine with me.
ها هو كلاي هانت. كان كلاي يعمل في البحرية معي.
We served together in Iraq and Afghanistan.
خدمنا سوياً في العراق وأفغانستان.
Clay was with us in Port-au-Prince. He was also with us in Chile.
كان كلاي معنا في بورت أو برنس. وكان معنا أيضا في شيلي.
Earlier this year, in March, Clay took his own life.
بداية هذا العام في شهر مارس، انتحر كلاي.
This was a tragedy, but it really forced us
لقد كانت مأساة، لكنه أجبرنا حقاً
to refocus what it is that we were doing.
على إعادة التركيز على ما كنا نفعله.
You know, Clay didn't kill himself because of what happened
كما تعلمون، كلاي لم يقتل نفسه بسبب ما حدث
in Iraq and Afghanistan. Clay killed himself
في العراق وأفغانستان. لقد قتل نفسه
because of what he lost when he came home.
بسبب ما خسره حينما عاد إلى الوطن.
He lost purpose. He lost his community.
لقد فقد الأمل. لقد فقد المجتمع.
And perhaps most tragically, he lost his self-worth.
وربما، الأكثر مأساة، لقد فقد قيمة حياته.
And so, as we evaluated, and as the dust settled
لذا، قمنا بالتقييم وانجلى الغبار
from this tragedy, we realized that, of those two problems --
عن هذه المأساة، لقد أدركنا أن هاتين المشكلتين --
in the initial iteration of our organization,
والدورة الابتدائية لمؤسستنا،
we were a disaster response organization that was using
لقد كنا مؤسسة استجابة للكوارث تستخدم
veteran service. We had a lot of success,
قدامى المحاربين. كان لدينا الكثير من النجاحات
and we really felt like we were changing the disaster response paradigm.
وقد اعتقدنا أننا بالفعل كنا نغيّر نمط التفكير تجاه الاستجابة للكوارث.
But after Clay, we shifted that focus, and suddenly,
لكن بعد تغيير كلاي لذلك التركيز، وفجأة،
now moving forward, we see ourselves
نحن الآن نمضي قدماً، نرى أنفسنا
as a veteran service organization that's using disaster response.
كمؤسسة خدمات لقدامى المحاربين تستخدم الاستجابة للكوارث.
Because we think that we can give that purpose
لأننا نعتقد بأنه يمكننا تقديم ذلك الأمل
and that community and that self-worth back to the veteran.
وذلك المجتمع وقيمة الفرد لقدامى المحاربين.
And tornadoes in Tuscaloosa and Joplin, and then later
والأعاصير في توسكالوسا وجوبلين
Hurricane Irene, gave us an opportunity to look at that.
ومن ثم الإعصار إيرين، أعطانا الفرصة لننظر لذلك الأمر.
Now I want you to imagine for a second an 18-year-old boy
الآن، أريدكم أن تتخيلوا لثوان ولدا عمره 18 سنة
who graduates from high school in Kansas City, Missouri.
تخرّج من ثانوية مدينة كنساس، في ولاية ميسوري.
He joins the Army. The Army gives him a rifle.
يلتحق بالجيش، فيعطيه الجيش بندقية.
They send him to Iraq.
ويرسلونه إلى العراق.
Every day he leaves the wire with a mission.
كل يوم يستلم برقية بمهمة.
That mission is to defend the freedom of the family that he left at home.
تلك المهمة هي الدفاع عن حرية الأسرة التي تركها في الوطن.
It's to keep the men around him alive.
والحفاظ على الرجال من حوله أحياء.
It's to pacify the village that he works in.
وتهدئة القرية التي يعمل فيها.
He's got a purpose. But he comes home [to] Kansas City, Missouri,
وقد وجد هدفاً. لكنه يرجع إلى مدينة كنساس، ميسوري، وطنه،
maybe he goes to college, maybe he's got a job,
ربما يلتحق بالجامعة، ربما يجد عملاً،
but he doesn't have that same sense of purpose.
لكنه يفتقد لنفس إحساس الهدف.
You give him a chainsaw. You send him to Joplin, Missouri
تعطيه منشاراً. ترسله إلى جوبلين، ميسوري
after a tornado, he regains that.
عقب الإعصار، يستعيد ذلك الهدف.
Going back, that same 18-year-old boy graduates from high school
نرجع إلى نفس ذلك الولد ذي الـ 18 ربيعاً من ثانوية
in Kansas City, Missouri, joins the Army,
في مدينة كانساس بولاية ميسوري، ينضم إلى الجيش،
the Army gives him a rifle, they send him to Iraq.
يعطيه الجيش بندقية، يرسلونه إلى العراق.
Every day he looks into the same sets of eyes around him.
كل يوم ينظر لنفس الأشخاص من حوله.
He leaves the wire. He knows that those people have his back.
يترك السلك، ويعرف أن هؤلاء الناس سيحمونه.
He's slept in the same sand. They've lived together.
لقد ناموا على نفس الرمال، وعاشوا سوياً،
They've eaten together. They've bled together.
لقد أكلوا سوياً، ونزفوا سوياً.
He goes home to Kansas City, Missouri.
يعود أدراجه إلى مدينة كنساس، ميسوري.
He gets out of the military. He takes his uniform off.
يخرج من الجيش، يخلع الزي الرسمي.
He doesn't have that community anymore.
لم يعد لديه هذا المجتمع بعد الآن.
But you drop 25 of those veterans in Joplin, Missouri,
لكنك ترسل 25 من قدامى المحاربين أولئك في جوبلين، ميسوري،
they get that sense of community back.
يعود لهم الإحساس بالمجتمع.
Again, you have an 18-year-old boy who graduates
مجدداً، لديكم شاب عمره 18 عاماً تخرج
high school in Kansas City.
من ثانوية مدينة كنساس.
He joins the Army. The Army gives him a rifle.
يلتحق بالجيش، يعطيه الجيش بندقية.
They send him to Iraq.
يرسلونه إلى العراق.
They pin a medal on his chest. He goes home to a ticker tape parade.
يعلقّون ميدالية على صدره. يعود لوطنه إلى موكب عسكري مصطف.
He takes the uniform off. He's no longer Sergeant Jones
يخلع زيه العسكري، لم يعد يعرف بالرقيب جونز
in his community. He's now Dave from Kansas City.
في مجتمعه. هو الآن ديف من مدينة كانساس سيتي.
He doesn't have that same self-worth.
ليس لديه ذلك التقييم الذاتي لنفسه.
But you send him to Joplin after a tornado,
لكنك ترسله إلى جوبلين عقب إعصار،
and somebody once again is walking up to him
ويقوم شخص ما مجدداً بالذهاب معه
and shaking their hand and thanking them for their service,
ويصافحه ويشكره، لخدمته،
now they have self-worth again.
الآن، يشعرون بقيمة أنفسهم مجدداً.
I think it's very important, because right now
أعتقد أنه مهم للغاية، لأنه الآن
somebody needs to step up,
ينبغي أن يتقدم شخص ما،
and this generation of veterans has the opportunity
ولدى هذا الجيل من قدامى المحاربين الفرصة
to do that if they are given the chance.
لفعل ذلك، إذا تم إعطاؤهم الفرصة.
Thank you very much. (Applause)
شكرا جزيلا لكم. (تصفيق)